It's time for our first LM experiment at this point.
첫 번째 달 착륙선 실험이에요
So some of this you may know well, you may know very well already.
이 중 일부는 이미 잘 알고 계실 거예요
For some people this might be new, but let me just explain.
어떤 사람들에겐 생소하겠지만 제가 설명해 드리죠
The models that we're going to be using.
우리가 사용할 모델이죠
These frontier models have been trained in a particular way.
개척 시대 모델들은 특정한 방식으로 훈련받았죠
That means that they expect two different types of instruction from us the user.
사용자가 두 가지 다른 종류의 지시를 내리길 기대한다는 뜻이죠
One of them is known as the system prompt, and one of them is known as the user prompt.
그 중 하나는 시스템 프롬프트고 다른 하나는 사용자 프롬프트죠
The system prompt is something which explains the context of this conversation.
이 대화의 맥락을 설명하는 시스템 프롬프트예요
It tells them what kind of task they're performing, what tone they should use, and we'll be experimenting
어떤 작업을 수행하고 어떤 톤을 사용해야 하는지 알려줍니다 또한 시스템 프롬프트를
with what it means to to change a system prompt and what kind of information that you can include in
변경하는 게 무슨 의미인지 실험할 겁니다 그리고 이 과정 내내 시스템 프롬프트에
the system prompt throughout this course.
어떤 정보를 포함할 수 있는지도요
The user prompt is the actual conversation itself.
사용자 프롬프트는 실제 대화 그 자체예요
And in our case right now, it's going to just be the the conversation starter.
지금 우리 경우엔 대화의 시작에 불과해요
And the role of the LM of the large language model is to figure out what is the most likely way that
큰 언어 모델에서 LM의 역할은 이 사용자 프롬프트에 따라 가장 잘 반응해야
it should respond, given this user prompt.
하는 방법을 알아내는 거죠
If it's given this user prompt, and in the context of this system prompt, what is the most likely
이 사용자 프롬프트가 주어졌을 때 시스템 프롬프트의 맥락에서 가장 다음에 나올 가능성이 높은
next text that will come after it?
텍스트는 무엇일까요?
That would come from an assistant responding to this user.
비서가 사용자에게 응답하는 거죠
So that's the difference between the system prompt that sets the context, the user prompt that is the
이게 컨텍스트를 설정하는 시스템 프롬프트와 대화를 시작하는 사용자
conversation starter.
프롬프트의 차이예요
So we're going to set a system prompt.
시스템 프롬프트를 설정할게요
And this is what it's going to say.
이렇게 말할 거예요
It's going to say you are an assistant that analyzes the contents of a website and provides a short
웹사이트의 내용을 분석하고 탐색과 관련된 문자를 무시하며
summary, ignoring texts that might be navigation related.
요약하는 보조라고 할 거예요
Respond in markdown.
가격 조정으로 응답하세요
You'll see more of what that means in in just a second.
그게 무슨 뜻인지 곧 알게 되실 거예요
So that is our system prompt for the user prompt.
이게 사용자 프롬프트 시스템 프롬프트예요
It's going to take as a we're going to write a function user prompt for.
이건 사용자 프롬프트 함수를 작성하는 것으로 받아들이죠
And it's going to take a website as the argument to the function.
함수에 대한 인수로 웹사이트를 취할 거예요
And it's going to say you are looking at a website titled The Website.
더 웹 사이트라는 웹사이트를 보고 있다고 하네요
The contents of this website is as follows.
웹사이트의 내용은 다음과 같아요
Please provide a short summary of the website in markdown if it includes news or announcements.
뉴스나 공지가 포함된 사이트라면 마크다운된 사이트를 짧게 요약해 주세요
Summarize these two and we then take the text from the website object that Beautifulsoup plucked out
이 둘을 요약하고 나서 웹사이트 객체에서 텍스트를 가져옵니다. 아름다운쏘프가
for us, and we add that into the user prompt and we return that user prompt.
뽑아낸 것이죠. 사용자 프롬프트에 추가하고 반환해요.
So let's just quickly let's run that cell right now and let's just have a look now.
그럼 빨리 셀을 실행해 보죠 지금 살펴보죠
So after doing that, if I just look at what system Prompt has.
그 다음에는 시스템 프롬프트가 무엇인지 보죠
It has that text of course that we just said.
방금 말씀드린 텍스트가 있죠
And now if you remember earlier on we created a new website object and we stored it in this variable
아까 새 웹사이트 객체를 생성해 이 변수 편집기에 저장했던 걸 기억하시나요?
So if I come here I should be able to say user prompt for and then pass in the object Ed.
이렇게 하면 사용자 프롬프트 for를 하고 객체 Ed를 전달할 수 있죠
And what we'll get is a prompt.
Get 프롬프트가 나오죠
It might be easier if I print this so that it prints out empty lines.
이걸 프린트해서 빈 선으로 프린트하는 게 더 쉬울 것 같아요
And here is the user prompt string that we've created.
여기 우리가 만든 사용자 프롬프트 문자열이 있네요
It says you're looking at a website titled blah blah blah.
웹사이트 이름이 어쩌고저쩌고라고 나오네요
The contents of this website is as follows.
웹사이트의 내용은 다음과 같아요
Please provide a short summary.
간단히 요약해 주세요
Look, it looks like we should have a space right here, otherwise it might be confusing.
여기에 공간을 만들어야 할 것 같아요 안 그러면 헷갈릴 거예요
Let's try that again.
다시 해 보죠
That's always why it's worth printing things as you go, because you'll spot little inconsistencies
그래서 작업을 하면서 인쇄할 가치가 있는 거죠 그런 모순을 발견할 수
like that.
있으니까요
I think it'll be nicer, actually, now that I look at that.
지금 보니까 더 좋을 것 같아요
If we have a carriage return there like so.
마차가 그렇게 돌아오면요
Let's have a look at this prompt.
이 프롬프트를 보죠
Now you're looking at the website and there we go on a separate line that looks good okay.
이제 웹사이트를 보면 별도의 라인이 있는데 괜찮아 보이네요
So let's talk about the messages object.
메시지 객체에 대해 얘기해보죠
So OpenAI expects to receive a conversation in a particular format.
오픈AI는 특정한 형식의 대화를 기대하죠
It's a format that OpenAI came up with and they used for their APIs, and it became so well used that
오픈AI가 개발한 포맷으로 API에 사용되었는데 너무 잘 사용되어서
all of the other major frontier models decided to adopt the same convention.
다른 주요 프론티어 모델들도 같은 방식을 채택하기로 했죠
So this has gone from being originally OpenAI's way of using the API to being something of a standard
API 사용에 대한 오픈AI의 방식에서 이 접근법을 사용하는 많은 다양한
across many different models to use this approach.
모델에 걸친 표준으로 바뀌었어요
And here's how it works.
이렇게 하는 거예요
When you're trying to describe a conversation, you describe it using a list a Python list of dictionaries.
대화를 설명하려고 할 때 파이썬 리스트를 이용해 설명하죠 사전 리스트요
So it's a list where each element in the list is a dictionary.
목록의 각 요소가 사전인 목록이죠
And that dictionary looks like this.
그 사전은 이렇게 생겼어요
It's a dictionary with two elements.
두 가지 원소가 있는 사전이에요
One of them has a key of role, and here the value is either system or user, a key of role.
그 중 하나는 역할의 키를 갖고 있는데 여기 값은 시스템이나 사용자, 역할의 키죠
And the value is system a key of content.
그 가치는 시스템 a 콘텐츠 키죠
And the value is of course the system message.
물론 가치는 시스템 메시지죠
There's another Dictionary where there's a key of role.
역할의 핵심인 사전이 또 있어요
The value is user because it's the user message.
값은 사용자입니다 사용자 메시지니까요
The user prompt content is where the user message goes.
사용자 프롬프트 콘텐츠는 사용자 메시지가 가는 곳이죠
User message and user prompt are the same thing.
사용자 메시지와 프롬프트는 같은 거예요
So hopefully I didn't explain it very well, but it makes sense when you see it visually like this.
설명이 부족했다면 몰라도 이렇게 시각적으로 보면 이해가 돼요
It's just a dictionary which has role and content, system and system, message user and the user message.
역할과 콘텐츠, 시스템과 시스템 메시지와 사용자 메시지가 있는 사전이죠
And there are some other roles as well, but we're going to get to them in good time.
다른 역할도 있지만 때가 되면 보여드릴게요. Get it.
This is all we need for now.
지금은 이거면 돼요
So this is how messages are built.
이렇게 메시지가 구축되죠
And if you look at this next function def messages for hopefully it's super clear to you that this is
다음 함수 데프 메시지를 보면 이게 생성되고 있다는 게 아주 명확했으면 좋겠네요
This here is creating exactly this construct using code.
이건 코드를 이용해 정확히 이걸 만들고 있어요
It's going to do it's going to put in there the generic system prompt we came up with.
이제 입력할 것은 우리가 생각해낸 제네릭 시스템 프롬프트예요
And it's going to create the user prompt for the website.
웹사이트의 사용자 프롬프트를 생성할 거예요
So let's run that.
실행해 보죠
And now, presumably it's clear that if I say messages for Ed, which is the object for my website,
제 웹사이트의 객체인 Ed를 위한 메시지라고 하면 빈 줄 같은
let's print it so that we see empty lines and stuff.
게 보이도록 프린트하죠
Actually, sorry, in this case it might be better if we don't print it.
사실, 죄송해요, 이 경우엔 프린트 안 하는 게 낫겠어요
If we just do this, it might look a bit clearer.
비트를 이렇게 하면 더 명확해 보일 거예요
There we go.
됐어요
And now you can see that it is it's a list of two things role system.
이제 두 가지 목록이 보이시죠 역할 시스템이요
And there's a system message role user.
시스템 메시지 역할 유저가 있어요
And there is the user message.
사용자 메시지가 있네요
Okay.
네
It's time to bring this together.
이제 하나로 합쳐야죠
It's time to actually do it.
이제 실제로 할 때예요
The API for OpenAI to make a call to a frontier model to do this for us is super simple, and we're
OpenAI의 API는 프론티어 모델에 호출하는 데 아주 간단합니다 이 API를
going to be using this API all the time.
늘 사용할 거예요
So whereas now it might look like it's a few things to remember.
지금은 기억해야 할 게 몇 가지 있는 것처럼 보일 수 있죠
You're going to get so used to this, but we're going to make a function called summarize.
익숙해지실 거예요 get Marize라는 함수를 만들 거예요
And that is that's going to do the business that's going to solve our problem and summarize a URL that's
그럼 우리 문제를 해결하고 통과한 URL 요약을 하게
passed in.
되죠
It will first create a website for that URL, just like we did for editor.
URL 웹사이트를 먼저 생성합니다 편집기에서 했던 것처럼요
And this is where we call OpenAI.
여기가 오픈아이라고 부르는 곳이에요
We say OpenAI, which is the the OpenAI object.
오픈AI라고 하죠 오픈AI 객체예요
We created OpenAI dot chat, dot completions, dot create.
OpenAI.챗, .완성, .Create를 만들었어요
And that for now you can just learn it by rote.
지금은 기계로 익히면 돼요
We'll understand a lot more about that later.
나중에 더 자세히 알게 될 거예요
But as far as OpenAI is concerned, this is known as the completions API because we're asking it to
하지만 오픈AI에 관한 한 이건 완성 API로 알려져 있습니다 이 대화를 완료하도록
complete this conversation, predict what would be most likely to come next.
요청하고 다음에 뭐가 나올지 예측하도록 요청하고 있으니까요
We pass in the name of the model we're going to use.
사용할 모델의 이름을 전달하죠
We're going to use a model called GPT four mini that you'll get very familiar with.
GPT for 미니라는 모델을 사용할 건데 여러분이 아주 익숙해지실 거예요
It is the light, cheap version of GPT four, the the one of the finest models on the planet, and this
GPT 4의 가볍고 저렴한 버전입니다 GPT 4는 지구에서 가장 좋은 모델로 사용
will cost fractions of a cent to use.
비용도 1센트도 들지 않죠
This, um, you pass in the model and then you pass in the messages and the messages we pass in, use
이건 모델을 통과시키고 메시지를 통과시키는데 우리가 통과시킨
this structure that we've just created and that is all it takes.
메시지는 방금 만든 이 구조를 사용하면 돼요
What comes back we put in this this object response.
Get in get은 객체 응답이에요
And when we get back the response we call response dot choices zero dot message dot content.
응답을 받으면 응답은 .선택 .0,Message.content라고 하죠
Now I'm going to explain what this is another day we don't need to know.
이제 이게 뭔지 설명할게요 알 필요 없는 또 다른 하루
For now.
지금은요
We just need to know that we're going to do response dot choices zero dot message dot content.
우리가 해야 할 건 응답 .선택 .0,Message.content예요
That's going to be it.
그렇게 될 거예요
That is our summarize function.
이게 요약 함수예요
And with that let's try summarizing my website we're running.
그것과 함께 실행 중인 제 웹사이트를 요약해보죠
It's now connecting to OpenAI in the cloud.
클라우드에서 오픈AI에 연결되고 있어요
It's making the call and back.
전화를 걸고 돌아오죠
Here is a summary of my website.
제 웹사이트의 요약본이에요
We have just uh, spent a fraction of a cent and we have just summarized my website.
저희는 그냥 아주 적은 돈을 들여서 제 웹사이트를 요약해 봤어요
We can do a little bit better because we can print this in a nice style.
좀 더 나은 게 있어요 멋진 스타일로 비트를 출력할 수 있거든요
Uh, GPT four, we've asked to respond in markdown, and that means that it's responded with various
GPT4에 마크다운으로 응답하라고 요청했는데 다양한
characters to represent headings, things in bold and so on.
캐릭터와 제목 등 굵은 글씨로 응답했다는 뜻이죠
And we can use a feature of Jupyter Labs that we can ask it to actually show that in a nice markdown
주피터 랩의 기능을 사용할 수 있습니다 멋진 마크다운 포맷으로 보여드리기 위해 요청할
format.
수 있죠
So let's do that.
그렇게 하죠
Let's use this display summary function and try again.
디스플레이 요약 함수를 이용해 다시 해보죠
Again we're going to GPT for a mini in the cloud.
클라우드에서 미니를 위해 GPT로 갈 거예요
And here is a summary of my website.
제 웹사이트의 요약이에요
Uh, it says something about me.
저에 대해 뭔가 말하는 것 같아요
Uh, and it's uh yeah, very nicely formatted, very nicely structured.
아주 멋진 형식이고 구조가 잘 짜여 있어요
Pretty impressive.
정말 인상적이에요
And apparently it highlights my work with proprietary LMS, offers resources related to AI and LMS,
보아하니 LMS 독점 작업을 강조하는군요 인공지능 및 LMS와 관련된 리소스를 제공하며
showcasing his commitment to advancing knowledge in this field.
이 분야의 진보된 지식을 위한 그의 노력을 보여주죠
Good for you, GPT for mini.
잘했어요, 미니 GPT
That's a very nice summary.
요약 잘하시네요
Okay.
네
And now we can try some more websites.
이제 다른 웹사이트도 살펴보죠
Let's try summarizing cnn.com.
cnn을 요약해 보죠 코무요
Uh, we'll see what this happens.
어떻게 될지 두고 보죠
Obviously, CNN is a much bigger, uh, result you've got here.
CNN이 훨씬 더 큰 결과를 가져왔죠
Uh, and, uh, we get some information about what's going on.
Get it, get it, get it it it, it
I'm actually recording this right now on the 5th of November at, uh, in the evening, which is the
지금 이걸 녹화하는 건 11월 5일 저녁이에요 2024년 선거일인데
date of the 2024 elections going on right now.
지금 진행 중이죠
So that, of course, is featured on CNN's web page.
CNN 웹페이지에도 그 내용이 실렸어요
We can also summarize anthropic, which is the website for Claude.
클로드의 웹사이트인 안드로픽도 요약할 수 있어요
And they have a nice page.
페이지도 좋고요
And here you go.
여기 있어요
And you can read more about it in this nice little summary of their web page.
웹 페이지의 요약본에서 더 자세히 읽어보세요
All right.
좋아요
And that wraps up our first instant gratification.
첫 번째 즉각적인 만족감을 맛보았네요
It's it's juicy.
육즙이 풍부해요
It's something where we've actually done something useful.
뭔가 유용한 일을 한 거죠
We've scraped the web.
거미줄을 긁어냈어요
We've summarized summarization is one of the most common AI use cases.
가장 흔한 인공지능 사용 사례를 요약해 봤는데요
So common it's useful for all sorts of purposes.
너무 흔해서 여러 용도로 쓸 수 있죠
We'll be doing it a few different ways during during this course, even in our week eight a sticky solution
이번 과정 동안 몇 가지 다른 방법을 사용할 겁니다 8주 차에도요 요약을 하는
will be using something that will do some summarization.
걸 이용한 끈적한 솔루션이 있죠
So it's a great, uh, thing to have experimented with already.
이미 실험해 본 거라서 정말 좋아요
So there are so many other business applications of summarization.
요약의 비즈니스 응용 프로그램이 아주 많아요
This is something you should be able to put to good use.
이건 좋은 일에 쓸 수 있어야 해요 Put it up Put it up Put it up Put it up Put it up Put it up Put it up Put it
You should be able to think of some ways you could apply this to your day job right away, or be building
이걸 당장 직장에 적용할 방법을 생각해내거나 요약하는 걸 보여주는
a couple of example projects in GitHub that show summarization in action.
예시 프로젝트를 깃허브에 만들 수 있어야 해요
You could apply it to summarizing the news, summarizing financial performance from a financial report,
뉴스 요약, 재무 성과 요약 재무 보고서, 이력서 자기소개서에
a resume, and a cover letter.
적용할 수 있죠
You could you could take a resume and generate a cover letter.
이력서를 가져가서 자기소개서를 작성할 수 있죠
Uh, there are so many different things you can do with summarization of of documents.
문서 요약으로 할 수 있는 게 정말 많아요
And also adding on to that the scraping the web angle of it.
거기에 거미줄 각도를 긁어내는 것도 추가했죠
So have a think about how you would apply summarization to your business and try extending this to do
요약법을 여러분 비즈니스에 어떻게 적용할지 생각해 보세요 이걸 요약법으로
some summarization.
확장해 보세요
There's also uh, for for the more technically inclined, uh, one of the things that you'll discover
기술적으로 좀 더 관련이 있는 분들을 위해 이걸 사용하실 때 여러분이 빠르게
quite quickly when you use this is that there are many websites that cannot be summarized with this
발견하실 것 중 하나는 이런 접근법으로 요약할 수 없는 많은 웹사이트들이 있다는
approach, and that's because they use JavaScript to render the web page and are rather simplistic.
겁니다 왜냐하면 웹 페이지를 렌더링하기 위해 자바스크립트를 사용하기 때문이죠 좀 단순해요
Approach has just taken the the just just made the requests the server call and taken what we get back.
접근 방식이 서버 호출을 요청해 get을 받는 거죠
But there's a solution.
하지만 해결책이 있죠
And the solution is to use a platform like selenium or others like it, or playwright, which would
해결책은 셀레늄 같은 플랫폼을 사용하는 거예요 페이지를
allow you to render the page and and do it that way.
렌더링할 수 있게 해주죠
So if you're technically inclined and have some background with that kind of thing, then a really interesting
기술적으로 뛰어나고 그런 경험이 있다면 흥미로운 도전은
challenge is to turn this into something that's a bit beefier and add selenium to the mix.
이걸 좀 더 우람하게 만드는 거예요 비트에 셀레늄을 넣고요
Um, as it happens, someone has already done that.
공교롭게도 누가 벌써 했어요
Uh, one of the students, thank you very much.
학생 한 명요, 고마워요
And if you go into this folder community contributions, you'll see a few different solutions.
이 커뮤니티 기부 폴더를 살펴보면 몇 가지 다른 솔루션을 볼 수 있어요
And one of them is a selenium based solution.
그중 하나가 셀레늄 기반 용액이에요
So you can always go in and just just look at that yourself.
언제든 들어가서 직접 볼 수 있어요
Or you can have a shot at doing it too.
당신도 할 수 있어요
And you'll find the solution in there.
거기서 해결책을 찾을 수 있어요
And if you do come up with a solution to that or to anything, I would love it if you were willing to
그것이나 다른 것에 대한 해결책을 생각해내신다면 기꺼이 코드를 공유해주시면 감사하겠습니다
share your code so that others can benefit from it.
다른 이들도 혜택을 받을 수 있도록요
Ideally, put it in the community contributions folder and be sure to clear the output.
이상적으로는 커뮤니티 기부 폴더에 넣고 OUTPUT를 확실히 지우세요
So you go to kernel restart kernel and clear outputs of all cells.
커널 재시작 커널로 가서 모든 셀의 출력을 비우세요
Otherwise, everything that you've got in your output would also get checked into code which which would
그렇지 않으면 결과물에 있는 모든 것이 코드 안에서 체크인 될 겁니다 비트가
just clutter things up a bit.
좀 어수선해지겠죠
So so do that.
그럼 그렇게 하세요
And then if you could submit a PR, a pull request, I can then merge that into the code.
PR, pull request를 제출할 수 있다면 코드에 병합할 수 있어요
And if that's a new thing for you, it is a bit of a process.
비트 박스가 처음이라면 좀 복잡할 거예요
There is a write up here for exactly what you need to do to make that work.
그걸 성공시키기 위해 정확히 뭘 해야 하는지 여기 적혀 있어요
Anyways, this was the first project, the first of many.
어쨌든 이게 첫 프로젝트였어요
It's a simple project, but it's an important one.
단순하지만 중요한 프로젝트예요
A very important business use case.
아주 중요한 기업용 유스케이스가 있어요
I hope you found it worthwhile.
보람이 있었길 바라요
I will see you for the next video when we wrap up.
그럼 저희는 마무리하고 다음 영상에서 뵐게요
Week one.
첫째 주에요
Day one.
첫날이에요